Register of the Uruguayan subject collection, 1918-1990
Hoover Institution Archives
Uruguayan Subject Collection,
1918-1990
XX808
2 manuscript boxes, 1 phonorecord (0.9 linear feet)
Hoover Institution Archives Stanford, California 94305-6010
Serial issues, pamphlets, leaflets, bulletins, studies, and sound recording, relating primarily to political conditions and elections in Uruguay, and to communist and guerrilla movements in Uruguay.
Administrative Information
Access
Collection is open for research.
The Hoover Institution Archives only allows access to copies of audiovisual items. To listen to sound recordings or to view videos or films during your visit, please contact the Archives at least two working days before your arrival. We will then advise you of the accessibility of the material you wish to see or hear. Please note that not all audiovisual material is immediately accessible.
Acquisition Information
Acquired by the Hoover Institution Archives.
Accruals
Materials may have been added to the collection since this finding aid was prepared. To determine if this has occurred, find the collection in Stanford University's online catalog Socrates at http://library.stanford.edu/webcat. Materials have been added to the collection if the number of boxes listed in Socrates is larger than the number of boxes listed in this finding aid.
Access Points
Uruguay--Politics and government.; Elections--Uruguay; Communism--Uruguay; Guerrillas--Uruguay; Communism; Uruguay; Phonorecords
Series Description
- SUBJECT FILE, 1918-1990. (Box 1)
  Pamphlets, leaflets, serial issues, studies, and bulletins, primarily concerning political and economic conditions. Includes material regarding the Tupamaro guerrilla movement
- AUDIOVISUAL FILE, 1973. (Record cabinet)
  One phonorecord of protest songs
Container List
- SUBJECT FILE, 1918-1990
  - General. Pamphlets, 1918-1980. Includes a history of Uruguayan political parties by Setembrino E. Pereda and a printed copy of the 1980 constitution (Box 1., Folder 1)
  - Economics. Serial issues and pamphlets, 1976-1980. Includes individual numbers of GEOSUR, published by the Asociacion Sudamericana de Estudios Geopoliticos e Internacionales (Folder 2)
  - Elections, 1989. Report, 1990 (Folder 3)
  - Left
    - General. Serial issues and pamphlets, 1975-1987. Includes material relating to human rights, student movements, the Frente Amplio, and the Plenario Intersindical de Trabajadores - Convencion Nacional de Trabajadores (PIT-CNT) (Folder 4)
    - Movimiento de Liberacion Nacional - Tupamaros. Pamphlets, 1971-1981. Includes material on the kidnapping of Dan Mitrione and anti-Tupamaro writings from rightwing perspectives (Folder 5)
    - Partido Comunista del Uruguay. Serial issues and pamphlet, 1972-1983. Includes text concerning Georgi Dimitrov (Folder 6)
    - Partido Socialista Uruguayo. Pamphlet containing a speech by Jose Diaz, 1967 (Folder 7)
  - Partido Blanco (Partido Nacional). Serial issues, 1986-1987 (Folder 8)
  - Women. "Declaracion de las Mujeres Uruguayas," statement, 1974[?] (Folder 9)
- AUDIOVISUAL FILE, 1973.
  - One phonorecord, "Tear Down the Fences!: A Desalambrar!," protest songs performed by Daniel Viglietti, 1973 (recorded in 1967) (Folder Record cabinet)